charlottein2012.com 2012-12-28

# Charlotte in 2012: Charlotte in 2012 Privacy Statement

Charlotte in 2012 is a nonprofit organization that serves as the Host Committee for the 2012 Democratic National Convention to be held in Charlotte, North Carolina. Charlotte in 2012 is a nonprofit organization exempt from taxation under section 501(c) (3) of the Internal Revenue Code.

Charlotte in 2012, which is also referred to as the “Host Committee” has created this privacy notice to explain how we use information that you may provide while visiting our website and to demonstrate our firm commitment to Internet privacy.

The Host Committee may modify this policy from time to time so we encourage you to check this page when revisiting this website.

## How We Use Your Information

When you register, contribute, sign up to volunteer, or take any other action on our site, we may ask you to give us contact information, including your name, address, telephone number, credit card number and information, and/or e-mail address. We may obtain information about you from outside sources and add it to or combine it with the information we collect through this site. We use this information to operate this site, send you news and information to you about the 2012 Democratic National Convention, volunteer opportunities and events, and to solicit and collect contributions to the Host Committee, to solicit your participation in programs, events and activities, and obtain and confirm RSVP’s to events and programs. We use your e-mail address to send such information by e-mail and may use your telephone number to call you for these purposes and to follow up as needed to collect information that the Host Committee is required by law to maintain.

We will not provide your e-mail address or your telephone number to any other person or organization other than the administrative arm of the Host Committee, New American City, Inc., also a North Carolina nonprofit organization; or the 2012 Democratic National Convention Committee; or other political or nonprofit committees and organizations participating in the Convention. Your e-mail address and telephone number will not be used by the Host Committee for any purpose except for the operations and programs of the Host Committee.

Submitting your personal information including e-mail address on this page will sign you up to receive future e-mails from the Host Committee.

## Credit Card Information; Protection of Personal Information

When you contribute to the Host Committee, we collect credit card information from you. That information is used solely for processing your contribution; is not maintained by the Host Committee; and is never disclosed to anyone, for any other purpose other than for processing your contribution, under any circumstances.

The Host Committee uses industry standard security measures to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. Our server is located in a locked, secure environment. Permission to access your information is granted only to you and Host Committee employees or contractors (including New American City employees and contractors) who need to know that information to provide services to you. Although we make good faith efforts to store information collected by this website in a secure operating environment, we cannot guarantee complete security.

## Children

Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulations establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we have designed our sites to block our knowing acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age-related information is requested.Parents with questions may email us at the contact email address below.

## Contributions to Host Committee–Public Information

The Host Committee is required to file with the Federal Election Commission reports publicly disclosing the name, address, occupation and employer of individuals who contribute to the Host Committee, and the amount and date of the contribution.

## Contributions to Host Committee—General Policies

As a matter of policy, the Host Committee (Charlotte in 2012) does not accept monetary contributions from corporations; and does not accept any contribution in excess of $100,000, any contribution from any political organization or any contribution from individuals registered as federal lobbyists under the Lobbying Disclosure Act. Contributions by individuals to Charlotte in 2012 are tax-deductible to the donor as charitable contributions, for federal income tax purposes, to the extent permitted by law. Contributions made to Charlotte in 2012 are not refunded unless Charlotte in 2012 determines that such contributions have been made in violation of applicable law or of the policies set forth above.

## Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Some parts of this site may be password-protected. We may use a cookie (cookies reside on your computer and are under the control of your browser) to enable you to return to password-protected areas of the website without having to re-enter your password. If you wish to disable these cookies, the help portion of the tool bar on most browsers will tell you how do that. If you set your browser to disable cookies, however, you may not be able to access certain parts of this site.

## Advertising

We may place online advertising with third-party vendors, including Google, which will be shown on other sites on the internet. In some cases, those third-party vendors may decide which ads to show you based on your prior visits to the site. At no time will you be personally identified to those third-party vendors, nor will any of the information you share with us be shared with those third-party vendors. If you prefer to opt out of the use of these third-party cookies on the site, you can do so by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page.

## Data Tracking

In order to better serve our supporters, we use cookies and periodically analyze web logs. We may also use third-party services such as Google Analytics. This helps us understand traffic patterns and know if there are problems with our website. We may also use embedded images in emails to track open rates for our mailings, so that we can tell which mailings appeal most to Host Committee supporters and volunteers.

URLs contained in emails may contain an ID that enables us to correctly identify the person who takes an action using a web page. We may occasionally present a shortened URL that references a longer URL which contains an id—we do this to simplify the display, to prevent links from becoming broken when copied, and to ensure compatibility with email programs which do not handle long URLs. When a shortened URL is displayed in an email, you will see the full URL in the browser’s address bar when you access the page.

## Links to Other Sites

The privacy policies and practices contained in this Privacy Statement do not apply to ANY external links. This Privacy Statement only applies to our site or any future sites that we may develop. It does not cover sites that are linked to by this site or sites for which we are not responsible (“linked-sites”). These linked-sites will have their own policies and practices which may be different from ours. We therefore encourage you to familiarize yourself with the policies and practices of the linked-sites, especially if you provide personal information to them.

## Amendments and Consent to This Privacy Statement

We retain the right to amend or otherwise update this Privacy Statement at any time. By using our site, you consent to the collection and use of the information as we have described. If we change our policies and practices, we will post the changes in our Privacy Statement so that you are always aware of them. With this knowledge, you can make an informed decision about whether you wish to provide personal information to us.

## How to Unsubscribe, Opt Out, or Correct Your Information

If you want to unsubscribe from mailing lists or opt out, review, update, or correct your information, you can do so at any time quickly and easily by sending an email to info@clt2012.com.

## How to Contact Us

Any questions regarding this Privacy Policy should be emailed to info@clt2012.com.
